<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Zakarias D. Gram</title>
    <link href="https://zdg5.github.io/academic-site/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://zdg5.github.io/academic-site" />
    <updated>2024-06-01T16:33:17-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Zakarias Gram</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://zdg5.github.io/academic-site</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Teaching Philosophy</title>
        <author>
            <name>Zakarias Gram</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://zdg5.github.io/academic-site/teaching-philosophy.html"/>
        <id>https://zdg5.github.io/academic-site/teaching-philosophy.html</id>

        <updated>2024-06-01T15:47:55-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    My primary goal as an educator is to help my students learn how to think, speak, and write critically. In addition, I seek to engender in all my students a love of learning and specifically an appreciation for the field of Classics. To achieve these&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>My primary goal as an educator is to help my students learn how to think, speak, and write critically. In addition, I seek to engender in all my students a love of learning and specifically an appreciation for the field of Classics. To achieve these goals, I teach through using several approaches, including visualizations, small group work, scaffolded writing assignments, etc. Primarily, though, I teach in a highly interactive discussion format, which I loosely structure and plan, but is still responsive to student interests and needs.</p>
<p>Presumably like everyone else pursuing a PhD in the humanities, I’ve often been asked what use an advanced degree in classics might have, or even the use of a liberal arts education as a whole. While I personally believe classics to be worth studying for its own good, the most important benefit of an education in classics, in my opinion, is learning the think critically. In a world filled with misinformation and polarizing views, the ability to consider carefully and dissect information with which one is presented is vital for our own good, as well as our society’s. As I teach, I intentionally bring in contrasting viewpoints to encourage discussion among students, and I challenge the assumptions and conclusions that my students express in discussion. Since this is done in a safe environment and in a kind manner, I allow my students to reflect about their own mental processes and model the kind of thinking they can use outside the classroom.</p>
<p>I also seek to build critical reading and writing skills in my students through scaffolded writing assignments. Whether it was through giving multiple, smaller writing assignments or by having students submit multiple pieces of a larger term paper one at a time to get review, I ensure that any writing assignment is not simply forgotten after it is turned in, but rather that students can use my feedback and discussions about writing with their peers to improve their proficiency. For instance, I set aside a class in my “Ancient Greek and Roman Medicine” course to discuss students’ writing. I noticed that the students tended to simply summarize material (rather than bringing in their own analysis) and use emotive language (rather than presenting their argument in a dispassionate way). After going through some examples together, discussing their impact on the reader, and working in small groups to workshop their own writing, I saw a significant improvement in the students’ work. Their writing was clearer, they felt more confident writing about their own ideas, and they understood the impact of appropriate language in their writing.</p>
<p>While pursuing my PhD at UCLA, I have taught and been a teaching assistant in eight courses so far, and I will continue teaching throughout the next two years. One aspect of teaching a varied roster of courses that has struck me is how, despite the differences in student backgrounds and subject material, I can always find ways to work with students who are eager to find ways of applying what they are learning to today’s world. Indeed, facilitating conversations and discussions about connections between the ancient and the modern world are some of the most enriching classes that I’ve taught. I taught a group of political science undergraduates in “Invention of Democracy,” students from a variety of medical and STEM fields in “Ancient Greek and Roman Medicine,” and philosophy students in “History of Greek Philosophy.” I used the opportunities of teaching these multi-disciplinary groups to promote a class culture of cooperation and interdisciplinarity, which helps all participants, including myself, think more critically about the subject material. While I was more knowledgeable about the classical world, these students often contributed their own ideas from their own disciplines about modern democracy, medical practices, contemporary philosophy, etc. I’ve taken this group-centered—rather than instructor-centered—approach and applied it across all the courses I teach. As a result, students feel empowered in their own capacity as learners and knowers and find much more utility and enlightenment in their learning about the classical world.</p>
<p>For the upcoming academic year, I am designing an undergraduate course on ancient women philosophers, such as Perictione, Hypatia, Sosipatra, Macrina, etc. I am particularly looking forward to teaching this course, as it presents an opportunity to reflect on the classical canon and the voices that are generally excluded from it. When I’ve led discussions on Sappho and Sulpicia in the past, students have always been very excited to find a female voice amidst the overwhelmingly male world in Classics, and they have been more willing to spend more time analyzing each word left behind by these women. Finding ways for our students (and ourselves) to reclaim the voices of suppressed and minoritized groups in the classical world is an important responsibility for the instructor in classics. However morally flawed the Greeks and Romans were, our presentation of them as “classical”—somehow fundamental and inspirational for our current societies and nations—can be jarring for the many individuals who are <em>not </em>generally represented in the classical record, or who were seen as “less than.” The biggest single group of such people must be women, and I believe it is important for us as classicists to seek out opportunities to include minoritized groups in meaningful and academically responsible ways in the classical world.</p>
<p>Teaching is a fundamental part of our academic work, as it is the clearest way that we can engage others in our research. I believe that we have a responsibility to help our students learn to think, read, and write critically as they move into their various professions and throughout their life. I also think that an understanding of the classical world is an important framework for our students to conceptualize the world around them, which we can help them to understand through our teaching.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>CV</title>
        <author>
            <name>Zakarias Gram</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://zdg5.github.io/academic-site/cv.html"/>
        <id>https://zdg5.github.io/academic-site/cv.html</id>

        <updated>2024-05-14T14:42:40-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Education Degrees Ph.D. Classical Studies, UCLA Advisor: David Blank M.Phil. Classical Studies, University of Cambridge Thesis: “Gregory of Nyssa’s Linguistic Argumentation in Ad Ablabium” Advisor: Myrto Hatzimichali Pass with distinction B.A. Classical Studies, Brigham Young University cum laude Additional Training Scholarship Articles Reviews Conference Presentation Teaching&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>Education</strong></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Degrees</span></p>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 113.96%;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 25.7728%;">Expected 2026</td>
<td style="width: 74.1868%;">
<p><strong>Ph.D. Classical Studies</strong>, UCLA</p>
<p><em>Advisor: </em>David Blank</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 25.7728%;">2020</td>
<td style="width: 74.1868%;">
<p><strong>M.Phil. </strong><strong>Classical Studies</strong>, University of Cambridge</p>
<p><em>Thesis: </em>“Gregory of Nyssa’s Linguistic Argumentation in <em>Ad Ablabium</em>”</p>
<p><em>Advisor:</em> Myrto Hatzimichali</p>
<p><em>Pass with distinction</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 25.7728%;">2019</td>
<td style="width: 74.1868%;">
<p> <strong>B.A. Classical Studies</strong>, Brigham Young University</p>
<p><em>cum laude</em></p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Additional Training</span></p>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 113.96%;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 26.1478%;">Expected 2026</td>
<td style="width: 73.8118%;"><strong>Graduate Certificate in Digital Humanities</strong>, UCLA</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>Scholarship</strong></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Articles</span></p>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 113.533%;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 26.1203%;">2021</td>
<td style="width: 73.8378%;">With Lincoln H. Blumell and Kerry Hull. “Eine griechische Votivschrift in der Tenri University Sankōkan Museum.” <em>Journal of Epigraphic Studies</em> 4: 91–98.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Reviews</span></p>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 113.248%;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 26.4377%;">2018</td>
<td style="width: 73.5203%;">With Lincoln H. Blumell. Book review of <em>Dionysios von Alexandria: De Natura (</em><em>περὶ φύσεως) Übersetzung, Kommentar und Würdigung, mit einer Einleitung zur Geschichte des Epikureismus in Alexandria</em> by Kilian J. Fleischer. <em>Journal of Hellenic Studies</em> 138: 299–300. </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Conference Presentation</span></p>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 112.963%;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 26.5042%;">2024</td>
<td style="width: 73.4537%;">“Speaking of God: A Reevaluation of Gregory of Nyssa’s <em>Ad Ablabium</em>.” North American Patristics Society (NAPS) Annual Conference: Chicago, Illinois.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 26.5042%;">2023</td>
<td style="width: 73.4537%;">“Response Paper, Religion and Philosophy Panel.” UCLA Graduate Student Conference 2023: <em>Knowing and Knowing Nothing: Learning, Teaching, and Apprenticeship in the Ancient Mediterranean</em>: Los Angeles, California.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 26.5042%;">2023</td>
<td style="width: 73.4537%;">“Papirius Fabianus: Philosopher or Declaimer?” Classical Association Annual Conference, Cambridge University: Cambridge, England.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 26.5042%;">2023</td>
<td style="width: 73.4537%;">“Diogenes of Oinoanda's Criticism of Plato's Psychology.” CAMWS Annual Conference: Provo, Utah.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 26.5042%;">2022</td>
<td style="width: 73.4537%;">“A Question of Substance: Neoplatonic Commentaries on Aristotle and the Problem of Substancehood.” Classical Association Annual Conference, Swansea University: Swansea, Wales.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 26.5042%;">2022</td>
<td style="width: 73.4537%;">“‘A Condemnation of Nature’: The Reception of <em>Propatheia</em> in Late Antiquity.” SCS Annual Conference: Virtual (on Zoom).</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 26.5042%;">2021</td>
<td style="width: 73.4537%;">“The Trajectory of Negative Theology in the Platonist Tradition.” CAMWS Annual Conference: Virtual (on Zoom).</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 26.5042%;">2019</td>
<td style="width: 73.4537%;">“A Philological Analysis of Religious Transformation.” CAMWS Annual Conference, University of Nebraska–Lincoln: Lincoln, Nebraska.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 26.5042%;">2018</td>
<td style="width: 73.4537%;">“The Pre-Existence of the Soul in Didymus the Blind’s Tura Commentaries.” SBL Regional Meeting for the Rocky Mountains–Great Plains Region, Brigham Young University: Provo, Utah.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>Teaching</strong></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">As Instructor</span> (UCLA)</p>
<p>Greek 16: “Intensive Greek” (eight-week summer course)</p>
<p>Latin 16: “Intensive Latin” (eight-week summer course)</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">As Teaching Assistant</span> (UCLA)</p>
<p>Classics 51B: “Art and Archaeology of Ancient Rome”</p>
<p>Classics 48: “Ancient Greek and Roman Medicine”</p>
<p>Philosophy 100A: “History of Greek Philosophy”</p>
<p>Classics M125: “Invention of Democracy” (cross-listed with Political Science)</p>
<p>Classics 20: “Discovering the Romans”</p>
<p>Classics 10: “Discovering the Greeks”</p>
<p><strong>Digital Humanities</strong></p>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 112.678%;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 23.5348%;">2023–current</td>
<td style="width: 76.4243%;">
<p><strong><em>Learn Greek and Latin</em></strong><em> </em>(<a href="www.learngreekandlatin.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">learngreekandlatin.com</a>)</p>
<p>Website built to inform and connect individuals who want to learn Greek and/or Latin outside of a university context with one-on-one instruction</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 23.5348%;">2023</td>
<td style="width: 76.4243%;">
<p><strong><em>Gospel of Thomas Online</em></strong><em> </em>(<a href="gospelofthomas45.wordpress.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">gospelofthomas45.wordpress.com</a>)</p>
<p>Website exploring the connections between the Greek fragments and Coptic text of the Gospel of Thomas</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 23.5348%;">2024</td>
<td style="width: 76.4243%;">
<p><strong>“Museum of the Fasti”</strong> (<a href="https://skfb.ly/oSX9Y">https://skfb.ly/oSX9Y</a>)</p>
<p>3D model of nine fasti and other Roman calendrical devices, intended to inform a general audience about the appearance and use of fasti</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>Service</strong></p>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 112.393%; height: 576.261px;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr style="height: 50.0208px;">
<td class="align-center" style="width: 23.7246%; height: 50.0208px;">2023–2024</td>
<td style="width: 76.2344%; height: 50.0208px;"><strong>Graduate Representative</strong> for UCLA Dept. of Classics</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 165.188px;">
<td class="align-center" style="width: 23.7246%; height: 165.188px;">2023</td>
<td style="width: 76.2344%; height: 165.188px;">
<p><strong>Assistant for Dept. of Classics</strong> at UCLA </p>
<p>led summer Augustine reading group, reorganized UCLA Classics Reading Room, edited department newsletter</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 160.969px;">
<td class="align-center" style="width: 23.7246%; height: 160.969px;">2022–present</td>
<td style="width: 76.2344%; height: 160.969px;">
<p><strong>Tutor</strong> in Greek and Latin for middle school, high school, and university students</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.0208px;">
<td class="align-center" style="width: 23.7246%; height: 50.0208px;">2022–2023</td>
<td style="width: 76.2344%; height: 50.0208px;"><strong>Co-organizer</strong> of 2023 Classics Graduate Conference at UCLA</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.0208px;">
<td class="align-center" style="width: 23.7246%; height: 50.0208px;">2017–2019</td>
<td style="width: 76.2344%; height: 50.0208px;"><strong>BYU Classics Volunteer Tutor</strong> </td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.0208px;">
<td class="align-center" style="width: 23.7246%; height: 50.0208px;">2018–2019</td>
<td style="width: 76.2344%; height: 50.0208px;"><strong>Eta Sigma Phi President</strong> for local chapter at BYU</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.0208px;">
<td class="align-center" style="width: 23.7246%; height: 50.0208px;">2017–2018</td>
<td style="width: 76.2344%; height: 50.0208px;"> <strong>Eta Sigma Phi Secretary</strong> for local chapter at BYU</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>Awards and Recognition</strong></p>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 112.821%;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 23.8837%;">2020–2022</td>
<td style="width: 76.0741%;">
<p><strong>Graduate Dean Scholar’s Award</strong> at UCLA</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 23.8837%;">2019–2020</td>
<td style="width: 76.0741%;"><strong>Faculty of Classics award</strong> at University of Cambridge</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 23.8837%;">2016–2019</td>
<td style="width: 76.0741%;">Various <strong>tuition scholarships</strong> at Brigham Young University </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 23.8837%;">2018–current   </td>
<td style="width: 76.0741%;"><strong>Phi Kappa Phi</strong> member </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 23.8837%;">2017; 2018</td>
<td style="width: 76.0741%;"><strong>Dean's List </strong>at Brigham Young University</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="align-center" style="width: 23.8837%;">2017     </td>
<td style="width: 76.0741%;"><strong>ORCA (Research) Grant</strong> at Brigham Young University </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>Languages</strong></p>
<p>Attic and Koine Greek: Advanced Reading</p>
<p>Classical and Medieval Latin: Advanced Reading</p>
<p>Sahidic Coptic: Intermediate Reading</p>
<p> </p>
<p>English: Native Speaking and Writing</p>
<p>German: Advanced Speaking and Writing</p>
<p>French: Advanced Speaking and Writing</p>
<p>Danish: Native Speaking and Writing</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Digital Projects</title>
        <author>
            <name>Zakarias Gram</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://zdg5.github.io/academic-site/digital-projects.html"/>
        <id>https://zdg5.github.io/academic-site/digital-projects.html</id>

        <updated>2024-05-14T14:42:31-07:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>About</title>
        <author>
            <name>Zakarias Gram</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://zdg5.github.io/academic-site/about.html"/>
        <id>https://zdg5.github.io/academic-site/about.html</id>

        <updated>2024-05-14T14:42:16-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Zakarias (Zak) was born in Denmark and grew up in Germany. He received his B.A. in Classical Studies from Brigham Young University (2019, cum laude) and his M.Phil. in Classics, specializing in Ancient Philosophy, from the University of Cambridge (2020, pass with distinction). He is&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    Zakarias (Zak) was born in Denmark and grew up in Germany. He received his B.A. in Classical Studies from Brigham Young University (2019, <i>cum laude</i>) and his M.Phil. in Classics, specializing in Ancient Philosophy, from the University of Cambridge (2020, pass with distinction). He is currently pursuing his Ph.D. in Classics at UCLA (expected 2026).
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://zdg5.github.io/academic-site/media/posts/1/IMG_3576-cropped.jpg" height="2715" width="2818" alt="A picture of Zak"  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://zdg5.github.io/academic-site/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_3576-cropped-xs.jpg 300w ,https://zdg5.github.io/academic-site/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_3576-cropped-sm.jpg 480w ,https://zdg5.github.io/academic-site/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_3576-cropped-md.jpg 768w ,https://zdg5.github.io/academic-site/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_3576-cropped-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://zdg5.github.io/academic-site/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_3576-cropped-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://zdg5.github.io/academic-site/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_3576-cropped-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    His primary interest lies in the intersections between the Greek philosophical tradition and early Christian writings. By the fourth century, many Christian writers were attempting to integrate philosophical concepts into their theological and moral systems in order to showcase Christianity as an intellectual religious movement. This effort results in some fascinating treatises that must carefully balance the doctrines from scripture with non-Christian philosophy. In this vein, Zakarias has written about the use of the moral concept <i>propatheia </i>(inherited from the Stoic tradition) in Didymus the Blind’s <i>Commentary on the Psalms</i> and the consequences for Didymus’ Christology, and on Gregory of Nyssa who similarly imports philosophical terminology and concepts from Aristotle’s metaphysical treatises and Porphyry’s <i>Isagoge</i> in his treatise <i>Ad Ablabium</i>.
  </p>

  <p>
    Zak's dissertation project will compare specific Neoplatonic commentaries with patristic scriptural commentaries. Other projects include the development of negative theology, from middle Platonism to the Neoplatonic and patristic theologies of the fifth and sixth centuries; ancient women philosophers; and the integration of Porphyry's <i>Isagoge </i>into Christian writings. Other interests include papyrology, digital humanities, Coptic, and Roman declamation.
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
